JASPER KATZBAN DESIGNER & ENGINEER

CONTACT

Email

jasperkatzban@gmail.com

Phone

(845) 667-6760

Portfolio

jasperkatzban.com

Github

@jasperkatzban

SKILLS

Creative

Adobe Suite, Figma, Sketch, Framer, Blender, Audio & Video Production

Technical

Python, C, C++, JS, React, HTML, CSS, MATLAB, Processing, GCP, AWS

Soft Skills

UX Research, Project Management, Project Documentation

SELECT COURSES

Sustainable Design

Collaborative Design

Software Systems

Data Science

Modeling & Simulation

Principles of Integrated Engineering

Quantitative Engineering Analysis

Materials Consumption & Impact

I work at the intersection of design and software engineering to create sustainable solutions for people and the planet.

Through my interests in experience design, software, and digital media, I seek to contribute to teams who support the public good.

EXPERIENCE

Ancient Ritual - 2021 to Present (Summer Internship, then Part Time)

Produced immersive experiences featuring theatrical lighting and custom sound design. Developed software tooling to support this workflow. Helped establish sonic branding and content identity.

OCCaM Lab at Olin College - 2021 (Research Position)

Implemented mobile analytics pipeline in Swift, Firebase, & Python to aid UX research on an AR navigation app helping blind and low vision individuals.

Freelance Design Services - 2018 to Present

Providing web design & development, content creation, and branding consultation services to non-profits and startups in the sustainability and social impact fields.

FEATURED PROJECTS

Senatr: Gamified Lobbying - Fall 2020

Helped create an educational game focused on lobbying and climate legislation, creating storyboards, visuals, and functional UI prototypes.

The Archives of Asterion - Spring & Summer 2020

Worked with award-winning creative studio Third Rail Projects to develop and publish a theatrical webVR experience. Created 3D assets and scripted gameplay and graphics in A-Frame and Three.js.

VR for Seniors @ Rendever - 2017 to 2018

Interned at an MIT spinoff utilizing VR to improve quality of life for seniors with dementia. Conducted data-driven UX research studies, which won awards at local Intel and Regeneron science fairs.

EDUCATION

Olin College of Engineering

BS Engineering: Design & Computing (2019-2023)

Recipient of 4-yr 50% Olin Merit Scholarship | GPA: 3.7

Westchester Community College

Gap Year Studies (2018)

Courses: Manufacturing I & II, Intro to CAD | GPA: 4.0

MIT Launch

Led design and fabrication of a 3D printer monitoring system at a competitive youth startup accelerator run by MIT Sloan.